# Shareef Rossetti

shareefrossetti@gmail.com | (613) 809-1674 | 619 Sora Way Ottawa, Ontario K1T0N8 | linkedin.com/in/shareefrossetti

## **PROFILE**

- Professional Business Developer with more than ten years of experience in the business development processes. Involved in
  product testing, management and development of new business opportunities. As a tenacious senior manager with a
  strong sales background, I have experience conducting market research to leverage customer insight, market needs,
  optimizing business performance, and creative positioning for all brands under my umbrella.
- Possess government Secret (level II) and Reliability status security clearance obtained 8/25/2020

## **CORE SKILLS COMPETENCIES**

- ✔ Brand Building
- ✔ Identity Creation
- ✓ Strategic Planning
- ✔ Product Development
- ✔ Project Management
- ✔ Creative Planning
- ✓ Trend Analysis
- ✓ Market Research
- ✔ Budget Management

- ✓ Leading Teams
- ✓ Sales and Marketing
- ✓ Negotiation and Teamwork
- ✔ Research and Strategy
- ✓ Multitasking Ability
- ✓ IT Networking
- ✓ Strong Business Acumen

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Account Executive**

Raftr (Ottawa, ON)

## Accomplishments

- Promoted to Account Executive for success in BDR role after nine months. New goals include closing both new and expansion accounts for a value-based Education Technology tool.
- Hunted and closed new brands which allowed for expansion sites valued up to \$600,000 ARR
- Contributed to exceeding team quota on a monthly and quarterly basis
- Created effective cold calling scripts and objection handling techniques
- Collaborated with operations, customer support, and product teams to ensure the onboarding and success of customers is continued in order to expand accounts.
- Brought decision makers and influencers into conversation to further increase the likelihood of deals closing
- Maintain and update the sales CRM
- Prepare and participate in regular account and pipeline reviews
- Maintain and update thorough knowledge of company products and services, as well as sales objectives, strategies and pricing

#### **Digital Marketing Specialist**

Software For Love (Ottawa, ON)

January 2022 – Present

#### Accomplishments

- Software for love is a non-profit organization that focuses on providing software solutions in exchange for charitable contributions.
- The responsibility ranges from different things, such as Social Media Content Creation, handling marketing analysis and SEO.
- Planning, development and execution of national digital programs and campaigns, including online advertising, website strategy and design, social media, mobile, and deliverables.
- Leading ongoing management of digital touch points (home page and top level sections), social networking landing pages, and mobile.
- Managing digital agency relationships, day-to-day production, as well as campaign budgets and schedules.
- Owning and maintaining site analytics, metrics, and campaign reporting.
- In depth knowledge of SEO and adwords programs.
- Presenting recommendations to team members and the CMO.

## Sales Development Representative

Raftr (Ottawa, ON)

Accomplishments

- Attain monthly, quarterly and annual sales quota targets on a consistent basis
- New business development and strategic account planning
- Manage, maintain and grow a vertical market develop into an expert in that domain
- Build market trust and company customer relationships
- Make outbound phone calls to new and existing customers in order to listen, promote and sell the company's software applications
- Work closely with the company team to ensure on-boarding success, customer satisfaction and problem resolution
- Maintain and update the sales CRM
- Prepare and participate in regular account and pipeline reviews
- Maintain and update thorough knowledge of company products and services, as well as sales objectives, strategies and pricing
- Promoted to Account Executive for success in BDR role after nine months.

## **Business Development Officer**

CABA (Continental Automated Buildings Association) (Ottawa, ON)

*July 2020 – September 2021* 

June 2021 – February 2022

## Accomplishments

- Identify and pursue revenue through dues and non-dues opportunities, (i.e., research project contributors, research sales, event registration, sponsorships, etc.) through innovative and existing marketing tools, with defined targets for annual revenue growth.
- Pursue non-member revenue opportunities and advertising in CABA's publications, which include the CABA iHomes and Buildings Magazine and CABA NewsBrief, sponsorships, research sales, research contributors and event registrations.
- Ensure that all outstanding revenues that appear on the aging report, including new members, sponsorships, research sales, research project contributions and event registrations are followed up with via verbal and written communications.
- Provide daily call summaries and weekly electronic status updates on the aging report and in the CRM that covers new
  membership, sponsorships, research sales, research project contributors and event registrations.
- Assist directly in the marketing, planning and program development of CABA and endorsed workshops and events.
- Establish an action plan to realize sales/marketing goals and objectives as outlined in CABA's marketing strategy.
- Assist with CABA's strategic planning, by working with CABA staff and volunteers.
- Identify and create new opportunities to enhance new revenue, using social networking and innovative marketing tools.
- Represent CABA at selected industry events through exhibit booth presence and sales/marketing activities at these events.

#### Marketing Account Manager

Demand Spring (Ottawa, ON)

Sept 2019 - April 2020

#### Accomplishments

- Research, identify, and generate new Sales Qualified Leads, specifically in our primary (technology and financial services), secondary (healthcare, education, and retail) and emerging industries (sports and entertainment, manufacturing, pharmaceuticals). I specifically focus on our primary target personas: VP/Director of Demand Generation, VP/Director/Manager of Marketing Operations or Marketing Automation, Chief Marketing Officer. Geographically, my efforts are focused on North America, primarily the US.
- Demand Spring is a B2B marketing organization and I specialized in using Marketo as a marketing automation platform as well as using Microsoft Dynamics as a customer relationship management system.
- I delivered complex marketing campaigns using: web apps, forms, landing pages, automated programs, campaigns and professional-grade HTML emails within Marketo.
- Methodically qualify, build, and manage an accurate sales pipeline; maintain a high volume of activity including outbound cold calls, inbound tele-qualification, emails, & social selling.
- Conduct and manage the sales cycle process from initial contact through to the hand-off of a TQL to our Sales team.
- Consistently exceed quota of 10 SQLs per month. To reach this target I engage in minimum 40-80 calls/day with follow-up emails or social selling messages, and 6-10 live connections per day.

2 | Page

- Evangelize Demand Spring's Revenue Marketing services.
- Thrive on the pace of a high growth organization while remaining highly organized, optimistic, and coachable.

#### Senior Business Development Specialist

Northern Micro (Ottawa, ON)

Sept 2015 - May 2019

## Accomplishments

- Successfully generated an average annual sales revenue of \$1.5M in technology and services sold.
- Responsible for overseeing the generation of new clients and managing existing sales accounts.
- As part of the B2B Marketing team I'd be responsible for crafting and sending email campaigns using Constant Contact. I was also responsible for tracking the metrics on these email campaigns to make sure they were successful.
- I delivered complex marketing campaigns using: web apps, forms, landing pages, automated programs, campaigns and professional-grade HTML emails within Constant Contact.
- Managing the CRM (Microsoft Dynamics) and the sales team that gather data, plans detailed strategy and tactics, develop
  contact databases to achieve and exceed annual sales and revenue targets.
- Leads and closes sales for new business in both Federal and Provincial government organizations.
- Drive record sales and the development of the best of breed technology solution with collaboration from top sales professionals and manufacturers.
- Increase profit margins by leading the technology sales solution from desktop to the data center to private, public, education sectors, Microsoft Dynamics AX ERP, VCE converged infrastructure, EMC Storage Solutions, Security Solutions, Microsoft, HP etc.
- Work to ensure the success of the sales and business development teams through diligent, organized and planned efforts to
  reach key client decision makers and secure potential sales opportunities for infrastructure operational analyses and other
  value-added service propositions.
- Follow internally researched leads, develop opportunities for viable projects and collaborate with other sales departments to create material handling solutions for our clients.
- Serve as the leading expert in branding products and services, value proposition and differentiators particularly as they relate to business forecasting.
- Execute various key events, presentations, to include senior executive meetings, business discussion, lunch and learn sessions etc.
- Close all sales through negotiation tactics and ensure the client's needs are met.

## **Business Development Representative**

OnPath Business Solutions (Ottawa, ON)

Oct 2013 - Sept 2015

## Accomplishments

- Managed the business development strategy through collaboration with businesses to discuss the benefits of the unique hardware/software/services that HP has to offer in the marketplace.
- Acquired IT knowledge to sell HP products and services such as Blade/Rack/Tower servers, POE switches, IMC monitoring software tool, SDN controller, NAS/DAS/SAN storage devices, cloud solution services and site assessments.
- Created a customizable network solution that fits perfectly with the client's infrastructure.
- Generated quality B2B leads for HP US & HP Canada campaign.
- Created a CRM Sales Force system to effectively execute sales.
- Developed quality lead reports for the Quality Assurance Team.
- Reviewed constantly the customer feedback and then suggested ways to improve the processes and customer service levels which increased the satisfaction rate from 75% to 88%.
- Motivated the team to achieve high success in lead generations.
- Led, supervised and assisted new trainees while ensuring the daily lead count was met.

#### Sales Manager

Byexpress Transportation/3PL Division (Ottawa, ON)

Apr 2012 - May 2013

## Accomplishments

- Increased the customer satisfaction rate by 25% by improving the customer service.
- Planned, supervised and coordinated daily activity of junior business analysts.
- Improved communication with the marketing department to better understand the competitive position.
- Directed the creation and implementation of a Business Growth Plan, and increased sales by 87% in margin.

#### Warehouse Factory Worker and Senior Packer

## Accomplishments

- Managed and maintained the warehouse to the highest safety standards.
- Performed various technician duties to ensure products met the highest quality before shipment.

# Customer Service Representative and Cashier

STAPLES Canada (Ottawa, ON)

Sept 2005 - Apr 2011

## Accomplishments

- Diligently managed sales and returns to catch fraudulent transactions.
- Led a team of trained eight employees in surpassing target sales performances.
- Constantly delivered customer satisfaction and hassle-free service, shown by responses in Staples' Customer Satisfaction Survey.
- Exceed sales targets of complementary products and created tangible solutions for customers.

EDUCATION		
Full-Stack Web Development Certificate Carleton University, Ottawa, ON Canada	2022	
Bachelors of Economics Carleton University, Ottawa, ON Canada	2011	

#### **AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS**

- Staples Superstar (Employee of the Month April 2009)
- Selected for Junior Achievement of Eastern Ontario All-Star Team- April 2007
- Community Awareness Award March 2005

## **CERTIFICATION AND TRAININGS**

- Technical proficiency includes Customer Relationship Management (CRM), MS Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Outlook, Publisher, Groove), AS/400, COALITION, and knowledge of SAP for collecting and manipulating distribution results
- IT Networking Trained (HP Certified) with extensive technical knowledge of the hardware, software and services offered to support an organizations networking infrastructure
- Desktop Operating System Concepts especially Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 8, VDI, Linux and Mac OS
- Drift Sales Certified successfully completed the Drift Conversational Sales Course on January 23rd 2020.

#### **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE**

- Finance Co-Chair, Carleton Relay for Life, Sept 2010 Apr 2011
- Administrative Assistance, Snowsuit Fund, Aug 2002 Sept 2005